# VISHAL KUMAR MAHATHA

#### CONTACT

9199581899

vishalkrmahatha@gmail.com

(im) linkedin.com/in/vishal-kumar-mahatha

Vill-Manpur, Bokaro, Jharkhand

https://github.com/Vishal9199

#### SKILLS

Data Analysis C++

Programming IOT

Google Cloud Python

Project Management Java Basic

Problem Solving Robotics

#### EDUCATION

**Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science** 

#### **Vellore Institute of Technology**

2020-2024 CGPA: 7.92

Senior Secondary(12th)

#### **LBS Senior Secondary School**

2018-2020

Kota, Rajasthan

92%

Matriculation(10th)

#### Chinmaya Vidyalaya

2016-2018

Bokaro, Jharkhand

91%

# COURSES/CERTIFICATES

- Google Cloud Computing Foundations Certification Course (<u>Link</u>)
- Advanced Cpp Training IIT Bombay(<u>Link</u>)
- Java Training IIT Bombay(Link)
- PHP and MYSQL Training IIT Bombay( <u>Link</u> )
- Java (Basic) Certificate HackerRank (<u>Link</u>)
- Improving software development productivity -Udemy (Link)
- Deep Learning Essentials IBM
- Operating Systems and you: Becoming a Power User - Google - Google
- Cisco Packet Tracer Cisco Networking Academy

## ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. State, District Level NCSC(Selected)
- 2. National Level, NCSC
- 3. JEE MAINS Qualified

#### PROFILE

Experienced technical specialist with a professional work history in the field of educational management field. Experience in Computer Science, Data Science, Core Java, C++, Python, IOT, Embedded Systems, Robotics. A strong IT professional with a B.Tech degree in Computer Science with specialization in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics from Vellore Institute of Technology.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Applied Data Science Intern**

SmartInternz 2023

During my internship at SmartInternz, I worked on a project titled "Predictive Medical Cost Analysis." I collected and prepared medical cost data, performed exploratory data analysis, developed predictive models using machine learning algorithms, and interpreted the results. This experience enhanced my data science skills and provided me with valuable hands-on experience in applied data science.

# **Technical Member**

Club: HumanoidXVITCC

2021-2022

- Contributed to programming, designing, and path-planning of a humanoid robot
- · Tasks included coding, designing, and developing path-planning algorithms
- Gained valuable experience in robotics
- Enhanced skills in teamwork and problem-solving

#### **District, State and National Level Participant**

Event: National Children's Science Congress (NCSC) Project

2015-2016

- Collaborated in a team for scientific research and experimentation.
- Developed a project based on a specific scientific topic.
- · Presented project at State and National levels.
- Demonstrated research, critical thinking, teamwork, and communication skills.

Participation in NCSC project at District, State and National levels, showcasing passion for science and commitment to innovative projects.

## **PROJECTS**

- IOT Surveillance Robot(in cloud)
  - IOT-Cloud based and can be controlled tracked globally
  - o Real-Time camera feedback, Microsoft Azure cloud, VM
  - o Collision avoidance, Live location coordinates in map
- Zerodha Automation : Copy Trading
  - Selenium WebDriver based Zerodha automation, is dynamically efficient for Hedge Funds Company
  - Multiple accounts accessed all at once
  - Accesses OTP from mail, sends P&L screenshots to mail
- . NLP for Sentiment Analysis
  - NLP model for any start-up to monitor client's feedback in a website(Good or Bad review)
  - Flask is used in the backend and TD-IDF, SVM for training the model and forms new dataset from real-time feedbacks and stores it

Hindi

• Medical Cost Prediction: Applied Data Science, Predictive Modelling

## INTERESTS

Stock Analysis

LANGUAGES

Chess English